

VÍCTOR PÉREZ PIQUERAS

Software Engineer - Scrum Master - Researcher



+34 601 13 94 14



victorperezpiqueras@gmail.com @victorperezpiqueras in victor-pérez-piqueras





ABOUT ME

I'm a professional, competent and passionate Software Engineer. I'm experienced in web development and frontend design, as well as backend and software architectures, which allows me to easily adapt to most job positions, being able to work as a full-stack developer.

I enjoy teamworking and pursuing sinergies to get the best of me and the team. I've developed most of my career in english and, thus, I can effectively communicate with my coworkers whether they speak english or spanish.

I'm devoted to clean code practices, design patterns, refactoring principles and continuous integration/deployment techniques. I'm also a solid Agile promoter and certified Scrum Master.

HARD SKILLS











Agile development & Scrum (PSM I



Clean Code, CI/CD, Testing 🌈



SOFT SKILLS

Self learning

Teamwork

Critical thinking

Creativity

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer & Product Manager

Jan. 2024 - Today

Product management and full stack development in the Innovation and Product Department. My duties included supporting the inception, design, prioritization and implementation of new software products for the company. Technologies: Angular, FLutter, AWS Cloud services in Python.

Full Stack Developer & Scrum Master

Nov. 2021 - Dec. 2023

Hired on behalf of TMConnected, developing its MCO product: a management and monitoring system for maintenance machinery fleets in the railway sector. I supported our international agile team as their Scrum Master by doing training, meeting facilitation, communication improvement, innovation in technical and value delivery practices. Technologies: Angular and microfrontends; AWS Cloud services in Python for a microservice-based backend architecture and ETLs.

Researcher

Feb. 2021 - Oct. 2021

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Research support staff in R&D&i project. Design and evaluation of multi-objective optimization algorithms. Technologies: Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib.

EDUCATION

Certified Cloud Practitioner • AWS

2023

2023

Professional Scrum Master II • Scrum.org

2021 - Today

PhD In Advanced Computer Technologies

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Part-time researcher at the Intelligent Systems and Data Mining Laboratory.

Masters Degree In Computer Science

2020 - 2021

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Multidisciplinary training and management skills. 5 distinctions with honours.

- TFM: "Scrum management software enhancement for automatic Product Backlog prioritization". Technologies: Angular, NodeJS, MySQL, AWS, Python. Mark: 10.

Bachelor's Bilingual Degree In Computer Science

2016 - 2020

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Mention in Software Engineering. 4 distinctions with honours.

- TFG: "TheProductOwnerd: Support tool for the Product Owner". Technologies: Angular, NodeJS, MySQL. Mark: 10.

First Certificate In English (B2) • Cambridge

2018

ADDITIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

SISTEDES - NTT Data Award for the best Masters Thesis

2022

National award for the best Masters Thesis on new methodologies and tools for software development.

Charles Babbage Award for the best Masters Thesis

2021

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Award for the best Master's Thesis of a multidisciplinary nature and business transfer in the Masters Degree In Computer Science.

Best Academic Record of the Masters Degree In Computer Science

2021

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha Average mark of 9,80.

Pictotrainer - Third Award • Esiiab • Hack For Albacity

2020

Web and mobile application for the training and rehabilitation of people with functional diversity, presented to the HackForAlbacity2020 competition in collaboration with the CRMF-IMSERSO.

